原創翻譯  雙語字幕
最新連載海外影視劇下載
請登陸 www.YYeTs.com
僅供交流學習  禁止商用盈利
翻譯     杏仁斯嘉麗   SophiaSaaaga   *PiPi*
翻譯     煮粥博士   承包瑞秋草
校對     魔法草
時間軸     噃噃Master   安斯Master   大圣法師
時間軸     Dr.shuanglu   倩倩碩士   貝殼博士
后期     8T
總監     somehacker   草草
卡西利亞斯法師
Master Kaecilius.
那個法事只會讓你懊悔
That ritual will bring you only sorrow.
虛偽
Hypocrite!
挑戰關卡  比利
Challenge round, Billy.
拜托  比利  開玩笑呢
Come on, Billy. You've got to be messing with me.
沒有  醫生
No, doctor.
《如此美好》  恰克·曼吉歐尼  1977年
Feels So Good, Chuck Mangione, 1977.
真是的  比利  你還說這個會很難呢
Honestly, Billy, you said this one would be hard.
-是1978年  -不  比利
- It's 1978. - No, Billy,
《如此美好》雖然是1978年登上榜單的
while Feels So Good may have charted in 1978,
但專輯是1977年12月發行的
the album was released in December, 1977.
-不  維基上說是197...  -再看看
- No, no. Wikipedia says it's a 19... - Check again.
這些無用的信息你都儲存在哪啊
Where do you store all this useless information?
無用  他單靠粗管短號就能上前十熱曲榜
Useless? The man charted a top ten hit with a Flugelhorn.
-怎么樣  比利  -1977年
- Status, Billy? - 1977.
拜托  我恨你
Please. I hate you.
"如此美好"  是吧
"Feels so good", doesn't it?
我來吧  斯蒂芬
I... I've got this, Stephen.
你該做的做完了  去吧  我們來縫合
You've done your bit. Go ahead, we'll close up.
-怎么了  -槍傷
- What is it? - GSW.
你居然還能保住他的命
It's amazing you kept him alive.
呼吸暫停  腦干測試
Apneic, failed the brain stem test...
和呼吸暫停反射測試均無反應
and the apnea reflex test.
我好像發現問題所在了  帕爾默醫生
I think I found the problem, Dr. Palmer.
你把一顆子彈留在了他的腦子里
You left a bullet in his head.
謝謝  它撞到了髓質
Thanks. It's impinging on the medulla.
我需要專家意見  尼克已經判了腦死亡
I needed a specialist. Nic diagnose brain death.
但我就是覺得不對勁
Something about that doesn't feel right to me.
我們得跑了
We have to run.
韋斯特醫生  你在做什么
Dr. West! What are you doing?
器官采集  他是捐獻者
Organ harvest. He's a donor.
別急  我可沒同意
Slow down. I did not agree to that.
我不需要你同意  我們已經判定腦死亡了
I don't need you to. We've already called brain death.
話說早了
Prematurely.
得為他準備進行枕下開顱手術
We need to get him prepped for sub-occipital craniotomy.
我不會讓你給死人開刀的
Not gonna let you operate on a dead man.
你看到了什么
What do you see?
-一顆子彈  -一顆完好的子彈
- A bullet? - A perfect bullet.
子彈加固過
It's been hardened.
子彈加固是用鉛銻合金
You harden a bullet by alloying lead with antimony.
有毒金屬
A toxic metal.
而且子彈直接接觸腦脊液
And that's leeched directly into the cerebral spinal fluid.
立刻造成中樞神經系統停擺
Rapid-onset central nervous system shutdown.
我們得走了
We got to go.
病人沒死  但他要死了
The patient's not dead, but he's dying.
還要采集他的器官嗎
Still want to harvest his organs?
我來協助你
I'll assist you.
不用  帕爾默醫生會協助我的
No! Dr. Palmer will assist me.
謝謝
Thank you.
影像引導  立刻
Image guidance, stat.
沒那個時間了
We don't have time for that.
你不能直接用手做
You can't do it freehand.
我能  我就要這么做
I can and I will.
這不是炫耀的時候  斯特蘭奇
This isn't a time for showing off, Strange.
那十分鐘前
How about ten minutes ago,
你錯判了死亡時間時呢
when you called the wrong time of death?
顱神經未受損
Cranial nerves intact.
韋斯特醫生  蓋住你的表
Dr. West, cover your watch.
你沒必要當著眾人的面羞辱他的
You know, you didn't have to humiliate him in front of everyone.
我還沒必要救他的病人呢  但是嘛...
I didn't have to save his patient, either. But, you know, I
我有時候就是忍不住
sometimes just can't help myself.
-尼克是個好醫生  -你來找我了
- Nic is a great doctor. - You came to me.
我想聽聽別人的意見
Yeah, well, I needed a second opinion.
你已經聽到了
You had a second opinion.
你想聽到好的意見
What you needed was a competent one.
所以你更該當我的待命神經外科醫生了
Well, all the more reason why you should be my neurosurgeon on call.
你可以做出很大貢獻
You could make such a difference.
我不能在你的屠宰場工作
I can't work in your butcher shop.
我在做截斷脊髓熔合術
Look, I'm fusing transected spinal cords.
以及刺激中樞神經的神經發生
I'm stimulating neurogenesis in the central nervous system.
我的工作在今后的年月里能拯救上千人
The work I'm doing is gonna save thousands for years to come.
而在急診室  至多就是救拿槍的笨蛋醉鬼
In ER, you get to save one drunk idiot with a gun.
是啊  我們急診室的人不過就是在救命
Yeah, you're right. In ER, we're only saving lives.
撈不到名聲  沒有CNN來采訪
There's no fame, there's no CNN interviews...
那我只能繼續用尼克了
Well, I guess I'll have to stick with Nic.
等等  你們不是...你倆沒...
Oh, wait a minute. You're not... you guys aren't...
什么
What?
上床吧
Sleeping together.
抱歉  我以為我厭惡的口氣能暗示我的意思了
Sorry, I thought that was implicit in my disgust.
其實非常明顯
Explicit, actually.
沒有  我有絕對不能跟同事約會的規矩
And no, I have a very strict rule against dating colleagues.
-是嗎  -我稱之為"斯特蘭奇準則"
- Oh really? - I call it the Strange policy.
太棒了  很高興有東西是以我命名的
Oh, good! I'm glad something's named after me.
我發明了一種椎板切除術手術
You know, I invented a laminectomy procedure,
但不知為何
and yet, somehow,
似乎沒人愿意管它叫"斯特蘭奇術"
no one seems to want to call it the Strange technique.
是我們一起發明了那個術式
We invented that technique.
不管怎樣  你的準則讓我受寵若驚
You know, regardless, I'm very flattered by your policy.
我...
Look, I'm...
我今晚要去參加個神經病學協會的晚宴
I'm talking tonight at a Neurological Society dinner.
一起來吧
Come with me.
又是去演講  真浪漫
Another speaking engagement? So romantic.
你以前可喜歡跟我去參加這類活動了
You used to love coming to those things with me.
-我們很開心的  -不  是你很開心
- We had fun together. - No. You've had fun.
那不是以我們為主  是以你為主
They weren't about us, they were about you.
也不僅僅是我
Not only about me.
斯蒂芬  什么事都是以你為中心的
Stephen. Everything is about you.
或許可以用連字符
Maybe we could hyphenate.
斯特蘭奇-帕爾默術
Strange-Palmer technique.
帕爾默-斯特蘭奇術
Palmer-Strange.
比利  都有什么
Billy! What have you got for me?
35歲的空軍上校
I've got a 35-year-old Air Force colonel.
穿實驗性裝甲壓碎了下脊柱
Crushed his lower spine in some kind of experimental armor.
中胸廓爆裂骨折
Mid-thoracic burst fracture.
嗯  我是可以幫忙
Yeah, well, I could help,
但還有50個人也能幫他
but so could 50 other people.
給我找點值得做的
Find me something worth my time.
68歲女士  晚期腦干膠質細胞瘤
I have a 68-year-old female with an advanced brain stem glioma.
你是想讓我破壞我的完美記錄嗎
Yeah, you want me to screw up my perfect record?
絕對不要
Definitely not.
22歲女性  腦內有電子植入物
How about a 22-year-old female with an electronic implant in her brain
以控制精神分裂癥  卻被閃電擊中
to control schizophrenia struck by lightning?
這個聽上去是很有趣
That does sound interesting.
能不能發給我...
Can you send me the...
收到了
got it.
沒事的  不會有事的
It's okay. It's gonna be okay.
他們做了什么
What did they do?
他們用直升機送你過來的
They rushed you in a chopper.
但找到你費了不少時間
But it took a little while to find you.
你在車里時  修復神經損傷的黃金時期就過去了
The golden hours for nerve damage went by while you were in the car.
他們做了什么
What did they do?!
11根不銹鋼針插入骨頭
11 stainless steel pins in the bones.
多處韌帶撕裂
Multiple torn ligaments.
雙手嚴重神經損傷
Severe nerve damage in both hands.
你在手術臺上躺了11個小時
You were on the table for 11 hours.
看看這些固定器
Look at these fixators.
沒人能做得更好了
No one could have done better.
我就能做得更好
I could have done better.
不
No.
給你的身體點時間愈合
Give your body time to heal.
你毀了我
You've ruined me.
我還要多久才能...
How long until I can tak...
斯特蘭奇醫生  你的組織還在愈合
Dr. Strange... those tissues are still healing.
那就加快速度
So speed it up.
把支架沿肱動脈伸入橈動脈下
Pass a stent down the brachial artery into the radial artery.
可能可行
It's possible.
是昂貴的實驗性療法  但有可能
Experimental and expensive, but possible.
有可能就行
All I need is possible.
張開
Up.
拿出點力氣來
Show me your strength.
這根本沒用
This is useless.
不是沒用的  你可以的
It's not useless, man, you can do this.
那回答我  學士
All right, answer me this, bachelor's degree.
你見過誰遭受了這么嚴重的神經損傷
Have you ever known anyone with nerve damage this severe
經過理療  康復了嗎
to do this, and actually recover?
有一個人
One guy, yeah.
工廠事故  脊椎斷了  癱瘓了
Factory accident, broke his back. Paralyzed.
他的腿日漸萎縮
His leg wasted away.
因為推輪椅  他肩膀疼
He had pain in his shoulder from the wheelchair.
他一周來三次
He came in 3 times a week.
有一天  突然不來了  我以為他死了
And then one day stopped coming. I thought he was dead.
幾年后  他在街上從我身邊走過
A few years later, he walked past me on the street.
-走  -對  走
- Walked? - Yeah, walked.
扯淡  拿他的病例給我
Bullshit. Show me his file.
從檔案館里找到他的病例得要點時間
It'll take me a while to pull the files from the archive.
但如果能證明你個自大鬼錯了
But if it proves your arrogant ass wrong,
那也值了
worth it.
我看過了你所有的研究
I looked at all your research.
讀了你發來的所有論文  這是行不通的
I read all the papers you've sent, it's no gonna work.
我覺得你并不明白  你傷得多重
I... I don't think you realize how severe the damages are...
-是這樣的  -最優秀的醫生都沒能做到
- Look, here's the thing, I... - The best have tried and failed.
我理解  是這樣的
Look, I understand. Here's the thing. I...
你要我做的事根本不可能  斯蒂芬
What you want from me is impossible, Stephen.
拜托
Come on...
-我還得考慮自己的名聲  -拜托
- I've got my own reputation to consider. - Come on.
埃蒂安  等等
Etienne, wait.
-我沒法幫你  -等等  別
- I can't help you... - Wait. No.
不不  等等
No, no, wait!
他不肯做
He won't do it.
他是個庸醫
He's a hack.
東京有種新手術
There is a new procedure in Tokyo.
他們培養捐獻者的干細胞
They culture donor stem cells and then
進行采集  然后3D打印個支架
harvesting them and 3D-printing a scaffold.
如果我能借到錢
If I could get a loan together, just...
-斯蒂芬  斯蒂芬  -一小筆  20萬
- Stephen... Stephen. - A small loan, 200,000.
你一直是掙多少花多少
You've always spent money as fast as you could make it
但你現在是在花你沒有的錢
but now you're spending money you don't even have.
或許該考慮停止了
Maybe it's time to consider stopping.
不  現在才更不能停止
No. Now is exactly the time not to stop.
因為  我并沒有好轉
Because, you see, I'm not getting any better!
但這已經不是求醫了  這是發瘋
But this isn't medicine anymore. This is mania.
有些東西就是治不好
Some things just can't be fixed.
-沒有工作的生活  -也還是生活
- Life without my work... - Is still life.
這不是末路
This isn't the end.
還有其他事能讓你的生命富有意義
There are other things that can give your life meaning.
什么  你嗎
Like what? Like you?
你現在該道歉了
And this is the part where you apologize.
你現在該走了
This is the part where you leave.
好吧  我也看不下去你再這么折磨自己了
Fine. I can't watch you do this to yourself anymore.
-太艱難了  是嗎  -沒錯
- Too difficult for you, is it? - Yes.
是的
It is.
看到你這樣令我心碎
It breaks my heart to see you this way.
不  別可憐我
No. Don't pity me.
我不是在可憐你
I'm not pitying you.
是嗎  那你為什么來
Oh yeah? Then what are you doing here?
帶奶酪和酒來
Bringing cheese and wine
好像我們是去吃野餐的老朋友
like we're old friends going for a picnic?
我們不是朋友  克里斯汀
We are not friends, Christine.
我們連情人都算不上
We were barely lovers.
你就喜歡悲劇故事  是吧
But you just love a sob story, don't you?
你現在就這么看我了嗎
Is that what I am to you now?
可憐的斯蒂芬·斯特蘭奇  施舍對象
Poor Stephen Strange, charity case.
他終于需要我了
He finally needs me.
又一個你可以拯救的人性渣滓
Another dreg of humanity for you to work on.
把他包扎好  讓他重新回歸社會
Patch him up and send him back into the world,
心里簡直要唱起歌
hearts just humming...
你非常在乎  是吧
You care so much! Don't you?!
再見  斯蒂芬
Goodbye, Stephen.
斯蒂芬·斯特蘭奇
我說的吧
喬·潘伯恩
拜托  拿出點真本事來啊
Come on, man! Where is the competition?
你話真多
Talk a lot!
喬納森·潘伯恩  C7-C8脊椎完全性損傷
Jonathan Pangborn, C7-C8 spinal cord injury, complete.
-你是誰  -胸部以下癱瘓
- Who are you? - Paralyzed from the mid-chest down.
雙手部分癱瘓
Partial paralysis in both hands.
我不認識你
I don't know you.
我是斯蒂芬·斯特蘭奇
I'm Stephen Strange.
是個神經外科醫生  曾經是
I'm a neurosurgeon. Was a neurosurgeon.
你知道嗎  我還真認識你
Actually, you know what, man? I do know you.
我曾經去過你辦公室  你拒絕見我
I came to your office once. You refused to see me.
我連你助理那關都沒過
I never got past your assistant.
你當時沒法醫治
You were untreatable.
治不好就得不到榮譽  是吧
No glory for you in that, right?
你從萬劫不復的病情中康復了
You came back from a place there's no way back from!
我也想找到我的康復之路
I'm trying to find my own way back.
潘伯恩  你還打不打了
Pangborn, are you in or you out?
好吧
All right.
我本來都放棄我的身體了
I'd given up on my body.
我以為我只剩下思維了
I thought my mind's the only thing I had left.
至少也該努力提升它一下
I should at least try to elevate that.
所以我去見大師
So I sat with gurus,
還有圣女
and sacred women.
陌生人抬著我上山頂去見圣人
Strangers carried me to mountain tops to see holy men.
最終  我找到了我的導師
And finally, I found my teacher.
我的思維得到了提升
And my mind was elevated.
靈魂得到了深化
And my spirit deepened.
-不知如何  -你的身體痊愈了
- And somehow... - Your body healed.
是啊
Yes.
還有更深奧的秘密等著我學習
And there were deeper secrets to learn there,
但我沒有體力去接受了
but I didn't have the strength to receive them.
我安于我的奇跡  回家來了
I chose to settle for my miracle, and I came back home.
你找的地方叫卡馬塔奇
The place you're looking for is called Kamar-Taj.
-但那里代價[價格]很高  -多少錢
- But the cost there is high. - How much?
我指的不是錢
I'm not talking about money.
祝你好運
Good luck.
玩球吧  來啊
Let's ball. All right, ball up!
尼泊爾  加德滿都
不好意思  打擾一下
Excuse me. Excuse me.
卡馬塔奇
Kamar-Taj?
你知道卡馬塔奇在哪嗎
You know where Kamar-Taj is?
找到安寧  找到自己
卡馬塔奇
Kamar-Taj?
Kamar-Taj...
好吧
Okay.
伙計們  我沒有錢
Look guys, I... I don't have any money.
你的手表
Your watch.
不  求你們了
No, please.
-我只剩這個了  -你的手表
- It's all I have left. - Your watch.
好吧
All right.
你在找卡馬塔奇
You're looking for Kamar-Taj?
真的嗎
Really?
你確定找對地方了嗎
Sure you got the right place?
那里看起來更...
That one looks a little more...
卡馬塔奇一些
Kamar Taj-y.
我曾經和你一樣
I once stood in your place.
我也曾經...
And I, too, was...
很不敬
disrespectful.
我給你點建議
So might I offer you some advice?
忘掉你自以為知道的一切
Forget everything you think you know.
好吧
All right.
這圣殿屬于我們的導師
The sanctuary of our teacher.
古一法師
The Ancient One.
古一法師  他真名叫什么
The Ancient One? What's his real name?
對了  忘掉我自以為知道的一切  抱歉
Right. Forget everything I think I know. Sorry.
感謝你...
Thank you for...
好吧  這是...規矩嗎
Okay, that's, uh... a thing...
謝謝
Thank you for...
你好
Hello.
謝謝
Uh, thank you.
也謝謝你
And thank you.
感謝你  古一法師  愿意見我
Uh, thank you, Ancient One... for... seeing me...
不客氣
You're very welcome.
-古一法師  -謝謝  莫多法師
- The Ancient One. - Thank you, Master Mordo.
謝謝  哈密爾法師
Thank you, Master Hamir!
斯特蘭奇先生
Mr. Strange!
其實是博士
Doctor, actually.
肯定不再是了
Well, no. Not anymore, surely.
你不正是因此而來的嗎
Isn't that why you're here?
你做了許多次手術
You've undergone many procedures.
-七次  對吧  -對
- Seven, right? - Yeah...
-好茶  -是啊
- It's good tea. - Yes.
你是不是治好了一個叫潘伯恩的人  他癱瘓了
Did you heal a man named Pangborn? A paralyzed man.
算是吧
In a way.
你幫了他  他又能走了
You helped him to walk again.
對
Yes.
你是怎么治好C7-C8脊椎完全性損傷的
How did you correct a complete C7-C8 spinal cord injury?
不是治好了
I didn't correct it.
他不能走  我讓他相信他能
He couldn't walk; I convinced him that he could.
你不是指身心治療吧
You're not suggesting it was psychosomatic?
你把斷掉的神經接好后
When you reattach a severed nerve,
是你  還是身體讓它痊愈
is it you who heals it back together or the body?
-是細胞  -而細胞被設定好
- It's the cells. - And the cells are only programmed
以特定的方式來痊愈
to put themselves back together in very specific ways.
對
Right.
如果我告訴你  你可以說服身體相信
What if I told you that your own body could be convinced
它能以各種各樣的方式痊愈呢
to put itself back together in all sorts of ways?
你是說細胞再生
You're talking about cellular regeneration.
這種技術非常尖端
That's... bleeding-edge medical tech.
所以你才在這里工作嗎
Is that why you're working here,
脫離醫院董事會的監管
without a governing medical board? I mean...
你的治療方法實驗性多強
just how experimental is your treatment?
非常強
Quite.
所以  你有辦法讓神經細胞重組自愈嗎
So, you've figured out a way to reprogram nerve cells to self-heal?
不  斯特蘭奇先生
No, Mr. Strange.
我知道如何調整精神力量  使身體更好地愈合
I know how to reorient the spirit to better heal the body.
精神力量...愈合身體
The spirit... to heal the body.
沒錯
That's right.
好吧
No. Al... Al... All right.
我們要怎么做  從哪開始
How do we do that? Where do we start?
不喜歡那張圖嗎
Don't like that map?
不是的  它真的很不錯
Oh, no. It's... it's really good.
只是...我以前見過這個
It's just... you know, I've seen it before.
在禮品店里
In gift shops.
那這張呢
And what about this one?
-針灸  厲害  -是吧
- Acupuncture, great. - Yeah?
那張怎么樣
What about... that one?
你是在給我看核磁共振圖嗎  難以置信
Showing me an MRI scan? I do not believe this.
畫每張圖的人  都只能窺視局部
Each of those maps was drawn up by someone who could see in part,
而看不到全局
but not the whole.
我為來這兒  花了最后的一點錢
I spent my last dollar getting here
買了張單程票
one-way ticket,
你卻在跟我說信仰治療
and you're talking to me about healing through belief?
你是一個通過鑰匙孔窺視世界的人
You're a man looking at the world through a keyhole,
你這一生  都在試圖擴大那個鑰匙孔
you've spent your whole life trying to widen that keyhole.
想看到更多  知道更多
To see more, to know more.
而如今聽聞  這鑰匙孔可以擴大
And now, on hearing that it can be widen
是以你無法想象的方式  你卻抗拒這個可能性嗎
in ways you can't imagine, you reject the possibility?
不  我拒絕是因為我不信天方夜譚
No, I reject it because I do not believe in fairy tales
什么脈輪  能量  信仰的力量
about chakras, or energy, or the power of belief.
根本沒有精神力量這東西
There is no such thing as spirit!
我們都由物質構成  別無他物
We are made of matter, and nothing more.
你只是一粒小小的  轉瞬即逝的塵埃
You're just another tiny, momentary speck
漂浮在這冷漠的世界里
within an indifferent universe.
你太妄自菲薄了
You think too little of yourself.
你自以為能看穿我  是嗎
You think you see through me, do you?
你才不能呢
Well, you don't.
我倒是看穿你了
But I see through you!!
你剛對我做了什么
What did you just do to me?!
我將你的魂體打出了你的肉體
I pushed your astral form out of your physical form.
那杯茶里加了什么
What's in that tea?
裸頭草堿[迷幻藥]  還是迷幻劑
Psilocybin? LSD?
就是茶
It's just tea.
加了一點蜂蜜
With a little honey.
剛發生了什么
What just happened?
那一瞬間  你進入了精神次元
For a moment, you entered the astral dimension.
-什么  -魂魄與軀殼不共生的地方
- The what? - A place where the soul exists apart from the body.
你為什么要這樣對我
Why are you doing this to me?
為了讓你明白你有多無知
To show you just how much you don't know.
睜開你的眼睛
Open your eye.
該死
Shit!
上帝啊  上帝啊
Oh god! Oh god!
不不不不不
No. No. No. No. No. No.
怎么回事
What's happening?
這不是真的  不是真的
This isn't real. This isn't real.
不是真的  這是...
This isn't real. This is...
上帝啊
Oh god!
不不不不不
No. No. No. No. No. No.
他的心率太高  有點危險
His heart rate is getting dangerously high.
我看他挺好的
He looks all right to me.
你自以為明白這世界如何運轉
You think you know how the world works?
你以為這物質宇宙就是全部了嗎
You think that this material universe is all there is?
何為真實
What is real?
你感官無法觸及之處  還有怎樣的奧秘
What mysteries lie beyond the reach of your senses?
在萬物存在的根源處  思維與物質交合
At the root of existence, mind and matter meet.
思維塑造現實
Thoughts shape reality.
這個宇宙不過無數個宇宙之一
This universe is only one of an infinite number.
無盡的世界
Worlds without end.
有些世界充滿仁愛與生命
Some benevolent and life-giving;
有些則滿是惡念與饑荒
Others filled with malice and hunger.
還有黑暗之地  存在著比時間更古老的力量
Dark places, where powers older than time lie...
貪婪地
ravenous...
等待著
and waiting.
在浩瀚的多元宇宙間  你是誰
Who are you in this vast multiverse,
斯特蘭奇先生
Mr. Strange?
你在禮品店見過這個嗎
Have you seen that before in a gift shop?
教教我
Teach me!
不
No.
不...
No...
不要
No!
不不不不  不要
No, no, no, no no no no!
不要  開門  求你了
No! Open the door! Please!
謝謝  各位法師
Thank you, Masters.
你覺得我不該趕他走嗎
You think I was wrong to cast him out?
五小時了  他還在你門口
5 hours later, he's still on your doorstep.
他身上有股力量
There's a strength to him.
頑固  自負  野心...我都見過
Stubbornness, arrogance, ambition... I've seen it all before.
他讓你想起了卡西利亞斯嗎
He reminds you of Kaecilius?
我不能再教另一個天賦異稟的學生學會強大法術
I cannot lead another gifted student to power,
再看著他被黑暗吞噬
only to lose him to the darkness.
我就沒有那樣
You didn't lose me.
我想獲得力量  打敗敵人
I wanted the power to defeat my enemies.
你給了我力量打敗心魔
You gave me the power to defeat my demons.
并遵守自然法則
And to live within the natural law.
我們永遠不能擺脫心魔  莫多
We never lose our demons, Mordo.
我們只能學會抑制它們
We only learn to live above them.
被偷的幾頁書還在卡西利亞斯手上
Kaecilius still has the stolen pages.
如果他成功破解  就能毀滅我們所有人
If he deciphers them, he could bring ruin upon us all.
黑暗的日子可能就要到來
There may be dark days ahead.
卡馬塔奇或許用得上斯特蘭奇這樣的人
Perhaps Kamar-Taj could use a man like Strange.
別把我擋在外面
Don't shut me out.
我沒別的地方可去了
I haven't got anywhere else to go.
謝謝
Thank you.
洗澡
Bathe.
休息
Rest.
或是冥想
Meditate...
如果你可以的話
if you can.
古一法師會派人來找你的
The Ancient One will send for you.
這是什么  我的咒語嗎
What's this? My mantra?
是無線網密碼
The Wi-Fi password.
我們又不是野蠻人
We're not savages.
時間會表明
我愛你多深
~
克里斯汀
魔法的語言和人類文明一樣古老
The language of the mystic arts is as old as civilization.
古代的法師
The sorcerers of antiquity
把這種語言的使用稱為"咒語"
called the use of this language "Spells".
但如果這個詞有違你的現代思維
But if that word offends your modern sensibilities,
你可以把它稱作"程序"
you can call it a "Program".
它是塑造了現實的源代碼
The source code that shapes reality.
我們汲取能量
We harness energy
來自多元宇宙其他次元的能量
drawn from other dimensions of the multiverse,
來施咒
to cast spells,
變出護盾
to conjure shields
和武器
and weapons
創造魔法
to make magic.
但是
But...
即使我的手指可以做到
even if my fingers could do that,
我的手也只是在胡亂揮舞而已
my hands would just be waving in the air. I mean,
我怎么才能達到你那種程度呢
how do I get from here to there?
那你是如何能連接斷裂的神經
How did you get to reattach severed nerves, and
一節一節地修復人的脊椎呢
put a human spine back together bone by bone?
多年的學習和練習
Study and practice. Years of it.
-斯特蘭奇先生  -叫我斯蒂芬就好
- Mr. Strange. - Stephen, please.
-那你是  -王
- And you are? - Wong.
王
Wong.
就單一個王嗎
Just Wong?
就像  阿黛爾
Like... Adele?
或者  亞里士多德
Or... Aristotle.
德雷克
Drake.
博諾
Bono.
阿姆
Eminem.
《幻日之書》
The Book of the Invisible Sun.
《新天文學》
Astronomia Nova.
《統御法典》
Codex Imperium.
《所羅門鑰匙》
Key of Solomon.
-你全都看完了嗎  -對
- You finished all of this? - Yup.
-跟我來  -好
- Come with me. - All right.
這個區域僅對法師開放
This section is for Masters only.
但如果有我的允許  其他人也可以看
But at my discretion, others may use it.
從《馬克西姆的啟蒙》開始看吧
We should start with Maxim's Primer.
你的梵文怎么樣
How's your Sanskrit?
我谷歌翻譯用得挺溜
I'm fluent in Google Translate.
吠陀  古典梵語
Vedic, classical Sanskrit.
那些是什么
What are those?
古一法師的私人收藏
The Ancient One's private collection.
所以禁止閱覽嗎
So they're forbidden?
卡馬塔奇沒有禁止閱覽的知識
No knowledge in Kamar-Taj is forbidden.
只有個別禁施的法術
Only certain practices.
除了至尊法師
Those books are far too advanced
那些書對其他人來說太過深奧
for anyone other than the Sorcerer Supreme.
這本書有缺頁
This one's got pages missing.
那是《卡里奧斯特羅之書》  是研究時間的
That's the Book of Cagliostro. A study of time.
一個前法師偷走了一個法事
One of the rituals was stolen by a former Master.
是個狂熱信徒  叫卡西利亞斯
The zealot, Kaecilius.
他還把前任圖書管理員吊了起來
Just after he strung up the former librarian,
并砍下了他的首級
and relieved him of his head.
現在我來守衛這些書
I am now the guardian of these books.
所以如果再有一本藏書被偷
So if a volume from this collection should be stolen again,
我都會知道
I'd know it.
你還不及離開這里就會沒命
And you'd be dead before you ever left the compound.
那如果只是逾期了呢
What if it's just overdue? You know?
會有什么逾期費嗎  打個傷殘什么的
Any... late fees I should know about? Maiming, perhaps.
知道嗎  以前大家都覺得我很幽默呢
You know, people used to think that I was funny.
他們是你的手下嗎
Did they work for you?
好吧  跟你談話真愉快
All right. Well, it's been lovely talking to you,
謝謝你給我找書  給我講恐怖故事
thank you for the books and for the horrifying story and
并對我進行人身威脅
for the threat upon my life.
現在我們將得到力量消滅背叛我們的人
We will now receive the power to destroy the one who betrayed us.
也是背叛世界的人
The one who betrays the world.
掌握懸戒是學習魔法必不可少的
Mastery of the sling ring is essential to the mystic arts.
懸戒讓我們可以在多元宇宙中穿行
They allow us to travel throughout the multiverse.
你所要做的就是集中精神
All you need to do is focus.
去想象
Visualize.
在腦海中勾勒出目的地
See the destination in your mind.
目光超越你面前的世界
Look beyond the world in front of you.
想象出每個細節
Imagine every detail.
畫面越清晰  召喚傳送門就會
The clearer the picture, the quicker, and easier,
越快  越容易
the gateway will come.
停下
And stop.
我想和斯特蘭奇先生單獨談談
I would like a moment alone with Mr. Strange.
沒問題
Of course.
-都怪我的手  -這和你的手無關
- My hands. - It's not about your hands.
這怎么會和我的手無關
How is this not about my hands?
哈密爾法師
Master Hamir.
有勞了  哈密爾法師
Thank you, Master Hamir.
你無法打得河流服從你
You cannot beat a river into submission.
你得順應它的流勢
You have to surrender to its current,
化其力量為己用
and use its power as your own.
我要放棄掌控  才能掌控它嗎
I... I control it by surrendering control?
那根本沒道理啊
That doesn't make any sense.
并非凡事都有道理  也并非都必須有道理
Not everything does. Not everything has to.
你的智力引領了你的人生
Your intellect has taken you far in life.
但它不會讓你更進一步了
But it will take you no further.
順從吧  斯蒂芬
Surrender, Stephen.
放下你的自負
Silence your ego
你的力量才會顯現
and your power will rise.
跟我來
Come with me.
-等等  這是不是...  -珠穆朗瑪峰
- Wait. Is this... - Everest.
-真美  -沒錯
- Beautiful. - Yeah, right.
很美  很冷  但...很美
Beautiful. Freezing, but... beautiful.
在這種溫度下  人只能存活30分鐘
At this temperature, a person can last for 30 minutes
-然后就會永久喪失身體機能  -太好了
- before suffering permanent loss of function. - Great.
但前兩分鐘內你大概就會休克
But you'll likely go into shock within the first 2.
什么
What?
-順從吧  斯蒂芬  -不不  不要
- Surrender, Stephen. - No, no!!! Don't!
-新來的怎么樣了  -即將見分曉
- How's our new recruit? - We shall see.
隨時了
Any second now.
不會吧  又來
No, not again.
或許我該...
Maybe I should...
-斯蒂芬  -王
- Stephen. - Wong.
-你要什么  斯特蘭奇  -魂體投射的書
- What do you want, Strange? - Books on astral projection.
-你還沒準備好  -放馬過來  碧昂斯
- You're not ready for that. - Try me, Beyonce.
得了  你聽說過她吧  她可是大腕啊
Come on. You've heard of her. She's a huge star, right?
你笑過嗎
Do you ever laugh?
得了  把書給我吧
Come on, just give me the book.
不行
No.
就在這個房間  你曾求我教你
Once, in this room, you begged me to let you learn.
如今我卻聽說  你質疑所有教導
Now I'm told you question every lesson,
而更喜歡自學
prefering to teach yourself.
就在這個房間  你曾要我睜開眼睛
Once, in this room, you told me to open my eyes.
如今我卻聽說  要盲目遵守毫無道理的規矩
Now I'm being told to blindly accept rules that make no sense.
比如不能在圖書館里開傳送門嗎
Like the rule against conjuring a gateway in the library?
王打我小報告
Wong told on me?
你的魔法法術進步很快
You're advancing quickly with your sorcery skills.
你需要一個安全的地方練習咒語
You need a safe space to practice your spells.
你現在處于鏡像次元中
You are now inside the Mirror Dimension.
永恒存在但不會被發覺
Ever present but undetected.
這里的事不會影響真實世界
The real world isn't affected by what happens here.
我們在鏡像次元中訓練  監視
We use the Mirror Dimension to train, surveil,
也會用它來控制威脅
and sometimes to contain threats.
千萬不要沒戴懸戒被困在這里
You don't wanna be stuck in here without your sling ring.
等等  抱歉  你剛說的威脅是什么意思
Hold on. Sorry, what do you mean, threats?
了解無窮的多元宇宙
Learning of an infinite multiverse
就也要了解無盡的危險
includes learning of infinite dangers.
如果我把所有你尚不知道的東西都告訴你
And if I told you everything else that you don't already know,
你只會倉皇逃跑
you'd run from here in terror.
話說  她究竟有多老
So, just how ancient is she?
沒人知道至尊法師的年齡
No one knows the age of the Sorcerer Supreme.
只知道她是凱爾特人  從不提起往事
Only that she is Celtic and never talks about her past.
你不了解她還追隨她
You follow her even though you don't know?
我知道她堅定不移  卻又高深莫測
I know that she's steadfast, but unpredictable.
無情  卻有仁愛之心
Merciless, yet kind.
是她成就了如今的我
She made me what I am.
相信你的導師
Trust your teacher.
切勿迷失方向
And don't lose your way.
-像卡西利亞斯那樣嗎  -對
- Like Kaecilius? - That's right.
你認識他
You knew him.
他剛來時  失去了所有摯愛之人
When he first came to us, he'd lost everyone he ever loved.
他悲痛欲絕
He was a grieving, broken man,
在魔法中尋找答案
searching for answers in the mystic arts.
他是個才華橫溢的學生  但自傲又頑固
A brilliant student, but he was proud, headstrong.
他質疑古一法師  排斥我們的教導
He questioned the Ancient One, rejected our teaching.
他離開了卡馬塔奇
He left Kamar-Taj.
他的門徒如羊群般跟隨
His disciples followed him like sheep
被偽教義迷惑
seduced by false doctrine.
-他偷了一個禁忌法事  對嗎  -對
- He stole the forbidden ritual, right? - Yes.
那是干什么的
What did it do?
別再問問題了
No more questions.
-那是什么  -這也是問題
- What's that? - That's a question.
這是個法器
This is a relic.
有些魔法太過強大  無法維持
Some magic is too powerful to sustain,
我們唯有將其注入物件之中
so we imbue objects with it.
讓它們去承受我們承受不了的負擔
Allowing them to take the strain we can not.
這
This
就是生命法庭權杖
is the Staff of the Living Tribunal.
有很多法器
There are many relics.
瓦圖姆魔杖
The Wand of Watoomb.
佛多之靴
The Vaulting Boots of Valtorr.
真是朗朗上口  對吧
Really just roll off the tongue, don't they?
我什么時候能有自己的法器
When do I get my relic?
-等你準備好  -我覺得我準備好了
- When you're ready. - I think I'm ready.
法器覺得你準備好了  你才算準備好了
You're ready when the relic decides you're ready.
現在
For now,
變出一個武器來吧
conjure a weapon.
好吧
All right.
戰斗
Fight!
就好像你命系于此
Fight like your life depended on it!
因為有一天  或許真會如此
Because one day, it may.
克里斯汀
我再給你發一次郵件
王
Wong?
好了
Okay.
首先  打開阿戈摩托之眼
First, open the Eye of Agamotto.
好吧
All right.
我的天
Oh my.
能不能...
What if...
多瑪姆
Dormammu.
黑暗次元
The Dark Dimension.
永生
Eternal life?
怎么...
What the...
停下
Stop!!!
干涉時空連續性是大忌
Tampering with continuum probabilitie is forbidden!
我只是...在照書上的指示操作
I... I wa... I was just doing exactly what it said in the book!
那進行法事的危險
And what did the book say
書上是怎么說的呢
about the dangers of performing that ritual?
我不知道  我還沒看到那兒
I don't know. I hadn't gotten to that part yet.
操縱時間會創建出時間分支
Temporal manipulations can create branches in time.
不穩定的次元開口
Unstable dimensional openings.
空間悖論  時間循環
Spatial paradoxes! Time loops!!!
你想被困在一遍遍重復的時間段里嗎
You wanna get stuck reliving the same moment over, and over, forever,
或是存在完全被抹去
or never having existed at all?
警告真的應該放在咒語前
Really should put the warnings before the spell.
你的好奇心可能會害死你
Your curiosity could have gotten you killed.
你不是在操縱時空連續性
You weren't manipulating the space-time continuum,
而是在破壞它
you were breaking it.
我們不打破自然法則
We do not tamper with natural law.
而是保衛它
We defend it.
你怎么做到的
How did you even do that?
你從哪學到的理解它所需要的
Where did you learn the litany of spells required
冗長的咒語
to even understand it?
我過目不忘
I've got a photographic memory.
所以才能同時拿到醫學和哲學博士學位
That's how I got my M.D. and Ph.D. at the same time.
你剛剛做到的
What you just did
需要的不僅是好記性
takes more than a good memory.
你就是為魔法而生的
You were born for the mystic arts.
-但我的手還在抖  -暫時還在抖
- And yet, my hands still shake. - For now, yes.
-不會永遠如此嗎  -我們不是先知
- Not forever? - We're not prophets.
你們什么時候才肯告訴我  我們是什么
When are you gonna start telling me what we are?
復仇者那樣的英雄
While heroes like the Avengers
保護世界免受實體傷害
protect the world from physical dangers,
而我們法師捍衛世界  抵御魔法威脅
we sorcerers safeguard it against more mystical threats.
古一法師是最新一位繼承了至尊法師頭銜的人
The Ancient One is the latest in a long line of Sorcerers Supreme.
他們可追溯至千百年前的魔法鼻祖
Going back thousands of years to the father of the mystic arts,
全能的阿戈摩托
the mighty Agamotto.
就是那個創造了被你魯莽借用的魔眼法器的法師
Same sorcerer who created the eye you so recklessly borrowed.
阿戈摩托在魔力強的地方造了三座圣殿
Agamotto built 3 Sanctums in places of power,
這些地方如今都是大城市
where great cities now stand.
那扇門通往香港圣殿
That door leads to the Hong Kong Sanctum,
那扇通往紐約圣殿
that door to the New York Sanctum.
那扇通往倫敦圣殿
That one, to the London Sanctum.
三座圣殿一起
Together, the Sanctums
生成了一面保護世界的盾牌
generate a protective shield around our world.
圣殿保護世界
The Sanctums protect the world,
我們法師保護圣殿
and we sorcerers protect the Sanctums.
抵御什么
From what?
其他次元里威脅我們宇宙的存在
Other-dimensional beings that threaten our universe.
比如多瑪姆
Like Dormammu?
你從哪知道的這個名字
Where did you learn that name?
我剛在《卡里奧斯特羅之書》里讀到的  怎么了
I just read it in the book of Cagliostro. Why?
多瑪姆存在于黑暗次元中
Dormammu dwells in the Dark Dimension.
超越時間
Beyond time.
他是宇宙征服者  世界摧毀者
He is the cosmic conquerer, the destroyer of worlds.
擁有無盡力量和無限渴望
A being of infinite power and endless hunger,
他想要侵略所有宇宙
on a quest to invade every universe
把所有世界都納入他的黑暗次元
and bring all worlds into his Dark Dimension.
他最渴望地球
And he hungers for Earth most of all.
卡西利亞斯偷的那幾頁
The pages that Kaecilius stole.
一種聯系多瑪姆
A ritual to contact Dormammu
并從黑暗次元中汲取能量的法事
and draw power from the Dark Dimension.
好吧
Okay.
我退出  我...
I'm out. I...
我是來治手的
I came here to heal my hands,
不是來打什么魔法戰爭
not to fight in some mystical war.
倫敦
London.
卡西利亞斯
Kaecilius!
不
No!!!
王  莫多
Wong? Mordo?
布里克街117A
有人嗎
Hello?
丹尼爾
Daniel.
他們任命你為這座圣殿的法師了啊
I see they made you Master of this Sanctum.
你知道那意味著什么嗎
You know what that means?
你會為保護它而死
That you'll die protecting it.
住手
Stop!
你到卡馬塔奇多久了  你叫...
How long have you been at Kamar-Taj, Mister...?
是博士
Doctor.
-博士先生  -我姓斯特蘭奇[是挺怪]
- Mr Doctor? - It's Strange.
也許吧
Maybe.
這又不由我來說
Who am I to judge?
你不知道怎么用  是吧
You don't know how to use that, do you?
什么
What?
別說了
Stop it.
叫你別說了
I said, stop it!
你阻止不了它的  博士先生
You cannot stop this, Mr. Doctor.
聽著  我都不知道"它"是什么
Why... look, I don't even know what "This" is.
它既是開始也是結束
It's the end and the beginning.
多數人變成少數人  變成唯一
The many becoming the few, becoming the One.
你要是不想說明白
Look, if you're not gonna start making sense,
我就再給你戴上它
I'm just gonna have to put this thing back on.
告訴我  博士先生
Tell me, Mr. Doctor.
聽著  我叫斯蒂芬·斯特蘭奇博士
All right, look. My name is Dr. Stephen Strange.
-你是博士  -對
- You are a doctor? - Yeah.
科學家
A scientist.
你懂自然規律
You understand the laws of nature.
一切事物都會變老死去
All things age. All things die.
最終  太陽將燃盡
In the end, our sun burns out,
我們的宇宙將變冷毀滅
our universe grows cold and perishes.
但黑暗次元
But the Dark Dimension...
那個地方超越了時間
it's a place beyond time.
夠了  我再給你戴上
That's it. I'm putting this thing back on.
這個世界不非得滅亡  博士
This world doesn't have to die, Doctor.
這個世界有權和其他很多世界一樣
This world can take its rightful place alongside so many others,
成為唯一的一部分
as part of the One.
偉大而美麗的唯一
The great and beautiful One.
我們都能永生
And we can all live forever.
是嘛
Really?
這個新時代烏托邦次元對你有什么好處
What do you have to gain out of this New Age dimensional utopia?
跟你  跟所有人一樣
The same as you. The same as everyone.
生命  永恒的生命
Life. Eternal life.
人們總是從善惡角度思考
People think in terms of good and evil,
但其實時間才是所有人真正的敵人
when really, time is the true enemy of us all.
時間會殺死一切
Time kills everything.
那你殺死的人呢
What about the people you killed?
那都只是微小  轉瞬即逝的塵埃
Tiny, momentary specks
漂浮在這冷漠的世界里
within an indifferent universe.
是的  你明白了吧
Yes. You see,
你明白我們在做什么了吧
you see what we're doing?
這世界不是它應該有的樣子
The world is not what it ought to be.
人類渴望永恒
Humanity longs for the eternal,
渴望超越時間的世界  因為時間奴役我們
for a world beyond time, because time is what enslaves us.
時間是一種侮辱
Time is an insult.
死亡是一種侮辱
Death is an insult.
博士
Doctor...
我們不求統治世界
We don't seek to rule this world.
我們求的是拯救它  把它交給多瑪姆
We seek to save it, to hand it over to Dormammu,
他才是一切進化的目的
who is the intent of all evolution,
才是一切生命存在的緣由
the Why of all existence.
至尊法師保衛生命
The Sorcerer Supreme defends existence.
是什么讓你前往卡馬塔奇  博士
What was it that brought you to Kamar-Taj, Doctor?
是教化
Was it enlightenment?
還是力量
Power?
你是想去被治愈  我們都是
You came to be healed, as did we all.
卡馬塔奇吸納了各種殘破的東西
Kamar-Taj is a place that collects broken things.
我們都是為治愈的希望而來
We all come with the promise of being healed,
但結果  古一只教我們些雕蟲小技
and instead, the Ancient One gives us parlor tricks.
真正的魔法被她據為己有
The real magic she keeps for herself.
你就沒想過她是怎么活得這么久的嗎
You ever wondered how she managed to live this long?
我在《卡里奧斯特羅之書》中看到了那些法事
I saw the rituals in the book of Cagliostro.
看來你知道
So, you know.
法事給了我
The ritual gives me the power
打倒古一  拆毀圣殿的力量
to overthrow the Ancient One and tear her Sanctums down,
好讓黑暗次元進來
to let the Dark Dimension in.
因為古一私藏的  多瑪姆會無私給予
Because what the Ancient One hoards, Dormammu gives freely.
生命  永生
Life, everlasting.
他不是世界的毀滅者  博士
He is not the destroyer of worlds, Doctor,
而是世界的拯救者
he is the savior of worlds.
不  拜托  看看你的臉
No. I mean, come on. Look at your face.
多瑪姆把你變成了兇手
Dormammu made you a murderer.
他的王國又能好到哪去
Just how good can his kingdom be?
你覺得這很有趣
You think that's funny?
不是因為那個
No. Not that.
有趣的是  你的懸戒丟了
What's funny is that you've lost your sling ring.
先生  要幫忙嗎
Sir, can I help you?
帕爾默醫生  她在哪
Dr. Palmer, where is she?
-先生  我們得...  -她在哪
- Sir, we need to get... - Where is she?
在護士站
The nurses station.
克里斯汀
Christine!
斯蒂芬
Stephen?
天啊  怎么
Oh my god. What...
你得馬上帶我找個手術室  就你一個人
You need to get me in an operating theater now. Just you.
快  我沒時間了
Now! I haven't any time!
-怎么了  -被刺了
- What happened? - I was stabbed.
心臟填塞
Cardiac tamponade.
你穿的是什么
What are you wearing?
胸腔沒問題
Chest cavity is clear.
不  血液  積在圍心囊
No, the blood... is in the pericardial sac.
不不不
No. No no no no no no no!
斯蒂芬  斯蒂芬
Stephen! Stephen!
撐住  撐住
Come on. Come on.
再往上一點
Just a little higher.
小心針頭
Please be careful with the needle.
斯蒂芬
Stephen?
-這是什么  -我的魂體
- What am I seeing? - My astral body.
你死了嗎
Are you dead?
不  克里斯汀  但我要死了
No, Christine, but I am dying.
對了
Right.
好吧
好  好吧
Yeah. All right. Okay.
我從沒見過這樣的傷口
I've never seen a wound like this.
你被什么刺傷了
What were you stabbed with?
我不知道
I don't know.
-我現在得消失了  -什么
- I'm gonna have to vanish now. - No, what?
別讓我死  好嗎
Keep me alive, will you?
好
Okay!
Okay.
糟了
Oh shit!
充電至200焦
醒醒  醒醒
Come on, come on.
斯蒂芬  醒醒
Stephen, come on.
再電我一次
Hit me again!
別這樣
Stop doing that!
提高電壓  再電我一次
Up the voltage and hit me again.
-不  你的心臟跳了  -照做吧
- No, your heart is beating! - Just do it!
天啊
Oh my God.
充電至360焦
不要碰觸病人  按電擊鍵
天啊
Oh god! Oh god!
-你沒事吧  -嗯
- Are you ok? - Yeah.
好了
Okay.
過了這么久  你突然出現
After all this time, you just show up here,
魂體飛出身體
flying out of your body?
我知道
Yeah, I know.
我也想你
I missed you too, by the way.
我給你發了郵件  你從來不回
I wrote you emails, but you never responded.
為什么要回
Why would I?
克里斯汀  我太抱歉了
Christine, I am so, so sorry.
我為一切道歉  你說得對
For all of it. I mean, you were right,
我是個徹頭徹尾的混蛋  我對你太不好了
I was a complete asshole. I treated you so horribly
你應得到更好的對待
and you deserved so much more.
別說了  你顯然是受驚了
Stop. You... you're clearly in shock.
到底怎么回事
I mean, what the hell is happening?
你去哪了
Where have you been?
西藥沒能治好我后
Well, after Western medicine failed me,
我去了東方  最終來到加德滿都
I headed East, and I ended up in Kathmandu.
-加德滿都  -對
- Kathmandu? - Yeah.
鮑勃·西格歌里唱的那個
What, like the Bob Seger song?
1975年的《美麗失意者》A面
1975, Beautiful Loser, side A. Yeah.
然后我去了一個叫卡馬塔奇的地方
And then, I went to a place called Kamar-Taj
跟一位叫古一法師的人
and I talked to someone
聊了聊  然后
called the Ancient One, and...
-所以你加入了邪教  -不是
- So you joined a cult. - No, I didn't.
不算是
Not exactly. No. I mean,
他們確實教我挖掘
they did teach me to tap into powers
我之前聞所未聞的能量
that I never even knew existed.
-聽起來就像是邪教  -不是邪教
- Yeah, that sounds like a cult. - It's not a cult.
-邪教徒就會這么說  -不
- Well, that's what a cultist would say. - Oh, no.
等等  斯蒂芬
Wait, Stephen, wait.
你想做什么
What do you think you're doing?
邪教集會我要遲到了
I'm late for a cult meeting.
-簡直是瘋了  -是啊
- This is insane. - Yeah.
你要去哪
Where are you going?
你能跟我說實話嗎
Can you tell me the truth?
一位強大的魔法師
Well, a powerful sorcerer,
把自己獻給了一個遠古實體
who gave himself over to an ancient entity
他能打破物理法則
Can bend the very laws of physics,
還拼命想殺了我
tried very hard to kill me,
但我把他銬在格林尼治村了
but I left him chained up in Greenwich Village,
回到那個地方最快的辦法是走傳送門
and the quickest way back there is through a dimensional gateway
我在清潔間開了一個
that I opened up in the mop closet.
好吧  不說算了
Okay. Don't tell me. Fine.
我真的得走了
Really do have to go.
斯特蘭奇
Strange!
你沒事
You're okay.
相對而言  是的  我沒事
A relative term, but yeah, I'm okay.
懸浮斗篷
The Cloak of Levitation.
它找上你了
It came to you.
了不起
No minor feat.
它可花心了
It's a fickle thing.
他逃走了
He's escaped.
-卡西利亞斯  -對
- Kaecilius? - Yeah.
他能隨意折疊空間和物質
He can fold space and matter at will.
他能在鏡像次元外折疊物質
He folds matter outside the mirror dimension?
-在真實世界中  -對
- In the real world? - Yeah.
-還有幾個  -兩個
- How many more? - Two.
我把一個丟在了沙漠里
I stranded one in the desert.
-另一個呢  -他的尸體就在大廳里
- And the other? - His body's in the hall.
多拉姆法師在門廳里
Master Drumm is in the foyer.
他被帶回卡馬塔奇了
He's been taken back to Kamar-Taj.
倫敦圣殿淪陷了
The London Sanctum has fallen.
只剩下紐約和香港的
Only New York and Hong Kong remain now
來抵御黑暗次元
to shield us from the Dark Dimension.
你保衛了遭受襲擊的紐約圣殿
You defended the New York Sanctum from attack.
這里的法師走了  需要一位新的
With its Master gone, it needs another,
斯特蘭奇法師
Master Strange.
不
No.
我是斯特蘭奇博士
It is Dr. Strange.
不是斯特蘭奇法師[碩士]或斯特蘭奇先生
Not Master Strange, not Mr. Strange,
是斯特蘭奇博士
Doctor Strange.
我成為醫生時  曾發誓不傷害他人
When I became a doctor, I swore an oath to do no harm.
而我剛剛就殺了一個人  我不會做第二次了
And I have just killed a man! I'm not doing that again.
我當醫生是為了救人而非殺人
I became a doctor to save lives, not take them.
你當醫生主要是為了救一條生命
You become a doctor to save one life above all others.
你自己的
Your own.
還是能看穿我  是吧
Still seeing through me, are you?
我看到的是我一直所見的
I see what I've always seen.
你過于膨脹的自我
Your overinflated ego.
你想回到之前  你能夠掌控一切的妄想
You want to go back to the delusion that you can control anything,
甚至掌控死亡
even death,
然而沒人能控制死亡
which no one can control.
偉大的斯蒂芬·斯特蘭奇博士也不行
Not even the great doctor Stephen Strange.
多瑪姆也不行
Not even Dormammu?
他能讓人永生
He offers immortality.
正是我們對死亡的恐懼給了多瑪姆生命
It's our fear of death that gives Dormammu life.
-他以此為食  -正如你以他為食
- He feeds off it. - Like you feed on him?
你跟我說掌控死亡
You talk to me about controlling death.
我知道你是怎么做的
Well, I know how you do it.
我看過了《卡里奧斯特羅之書》里缺失的法事
I've seen the missing rituals from the book of Cagliostro.
千萬當心你接下來要說的話  博士
Measure your next words very carefully, doctor.
因為你可能不喜歡聽嗎
Because you might not like them?
因為你可能不知道你在說什么
Because you may not know of what you speak.
-他在說什么  -我在說她的長命
- What is he talking about? - I'm talking about her long life.
她不死的緣由
The source of her immortality.
她從黑暗次元汲取能量來維持生命
She draws power from the Dark Dimension to stay alive.
那不是真的
That's not true.
我見過那些法事  想明白了
I've seen the rituals, worked them out.
我知道你是怎么做的
I know how you do it.
等他們重組  狂熱信徒就會回來
Once they regroup, the zealots will be back.
你們會需要支援
You'll need reinforcements.
她不是你以為的那樣
She is not who you think she is.
你沒資格那么說
You don't have the right to say that.
你不知道她肩上擔負的責任
You've no idea the responsibility that rests upon her shoulders.
對  我也不想知道
No, and I don't want to know.
-你是個懦夫  -因為我不是個殺手嗎
- You're a coward. - Because I'm not a killer?
狂熱信徒會把我們統統消滅
These zealots will snuff us all out,
而你卻不能振作起來  先消滅他們
and you can't muster the strength to snuff them first?
-你以為我剛剛做了什么  -你救了你自己
- What do you think I just did? - You saved your own life!
然后像只受傷的狗一樣不停抱怨
And then whined about it like a wounded dog.
而你就能輕松做到嗎
You would have done it so easily?
你無法想象
You've no idea,
我做過的事
the things I've done...
答案是沒錯
And the answer is yes.
-毫不猶豫  -即使還有別的辦法
- Without hesitation. - Even if there's another way?
-沒有別的辦法  -是你缺乏想象力
- There is no other way. - You lack imagination.
不  斯蒂芬
No, Stephen.
是你缺少骨氣
You lack a spine.
他們回來了
They're back.
我們得了結此事
We have to end this.
快
Now!
斯特蘭奇  下來戰斗
Strange! Get down here and fight!
不要
No.
鏡像次元
The Mirror Dimension.
你在這里無法影響真實世界
You can't affect the real world in here.
現在是誰得意呢  混蛋
Who's laughing now, asshole?
是我
I am.
我拿了他的懸戒  他們跑不了的  對吧
I've got his sling ring. I mean, they can't escape, right?
快跑
Run!
他們與黑暗次元的聯系
Their connection to the Dark Dimension
使他們在鏡像次元里更為強大
makes them more powerful in the Mirror Dimension.
他們不能影響真實世界  但還是能殺了我們
They can't affect the real world, but they can still kill us.
這并不明智
This wasn't cleverness.
這是自殺
It was suicide!
真好笑
That is hilarious.
這是個錯誤
This was a mistake.
是真的
It's true.
她真的從黑暗次元汲取能量
She does draw power from the Dark Dimension.
卡西利亞斯
Kaecilius.
我投奔你時
I came to you,
心碎
broken,
迷失
lost,
需要幫助
in need.
我信任你做我的導師  你卻滿口謊言
Trusted you to be my teacher, and you fed me lies.
我是想保護你
I tried to protect you.
-真相會傷害我嗎  -你自己會
- From the truth? - From yourself.
如今我有新導師了
I have a new teacher now.
多瑪姆在欺騙你
Dormammu deceives you.
你不知道他的真面目
You have no idea what he truly is.
他所謂的永生并非天堂  而是無盡的煎熬
His eternal life is not paradise, but torment.
騙子
Liar.
克里斯汀
Christine!
開什么玩笑
Are you kidding me?
我的天
Oh my god.
不是心房顫動  她心肌頓抑
It's not fibrillation. She has a stunned myocardium.
-神經性休克嗎  -對
- Neurogenic? - Yes.
拿棉簽
Someone get the swabs.
尼克
Nic?
我們得降低她的腦壓
We need to relieve the pressure on her brain.
她心率在下降
She's still dropping.
她快不行了
We're losing her!
得給她加氧
We need to increase her oxygen!
-急救車推過來  -她的瞳孔放大了
- I need a crash cart! - Her pupils have dilated!
無反射能力  也讀不到腦部活動了
No reflexes. We're not reading any brain activity.
你在做什么
What are you doing?
別這樣  你快死了
Come on. You're dying!
你得馬上回到身體里  你沒時間了
You have to return to your body now. You don't have time.
時間是相對的  你的身體還沒倒地呢
Time is relative. Your body hasn't even hit the floor yet.
我花了太多歲月窺視未來
I've spent so many years peering through time,
看這一刻
looking at this exact moment.
卻看不到之后
But I can't see past it.
我阻止了無數種可怕的未來
I've prevented countless terrible futures.
一次接著一次  永無休止
And after each one, there's always another.
都將我帶到這一刻
And they all lead here,
但也止于這一刻
but never further.
你覺得自己死于這一刻
You think this is where you die.
想知道我在你的未來看到什么嗎
You wonder what I see in your future?
不想
No.
想
Yes.
我從未看到過你的未來  只能看到其可能性
I never saw your future. Only its possibilities.
你有行大善的能力
You have such a capacity for goodness.
你總是很出眾
You always excelled,
但并非因為你渴望成功
but not because you crave success,
而是因為你害怕失敗
but because of your fear of failure.
正因此我才是一位優秀的醫生
That's what made me a great doctor.
正因此你無法成就偉業
It's precisely what kept you from greatness.
傲慢和恐懼仍絆著你
Arrogance and fear still keep you
讓你無法學會最簡單也最重要的一課
from learning the simplest and most significant lesson of all.
是什么
Which is?
你并不重要
It's not about you.
你第一次來找我時
When you first came to me,
問我是如何治愈了喬納森·潘伯恩
you asked me how I was able to heal Jonathan Pangborn.
我沒有
I didn't.
他將次元能量引入體內
He channels dimensional energy directly into his own body.
-他靠魔法行走  -時刻如此
- He uses magic to walk. - Constantly.
他可以選擇
He had a choice,
是回到原來的生活
to return to his own life
還是為比小我更偉大的事業做貢獻
or to serve something greater than himself.
所以我的手能復原嗎
So, I could have my hands back again?
我能回到從前的生活嗎
My old life?
可以
You could.
而世界會因此變得更加危險
And the world would be all the lesser for it.
我厭惡從黑暗次元汲取能量
I've hated drawing power from the Dark Dimension.
但你知道
But as you well know,
人有時必須打破規則
sometimes one must break the rules
才能夠成就偉大的事業
in order to serve the greater good.
莫多不會這么覺得
Mordo won't see it that way.
莫多的靈魂剛強不屈
Mordo's soul is rigid and unmovable,
那是他青春的火焰鍛造的品性
forged by the fires of his youth.
他需要你的變通  就像你需要他的力量
He needs your flexibility, just as you need his strength.
你們只有共同努力  才有希望阻止多瑪姆
Only together do you stand a chance of stopping Dormammu.
我還沒準備好
I'm not ready.
沒人會準備好
No one ever is.
時機由不得我們選
We don't get to choose our time.
是死亡賦予了生命意義
Death is what gives life meaning.
知道自己生命有限
To know your days are numbered,
人生苦短
your time is short.
按說都這么久了  我應該準備好了
You'd think after all this time I'd be ready.
但你看看我
But look at me,
無限延長片刻時間
stretching one moment out into a thousand,
就為了看雪景
just so that I can watch the snow.
你還好嗎
Are you okay?
-我不明白是怎么回事  -我知道
- I don't understand what's happening. - I know.
但我得走了
But I have to go away now.
你曾說失去我的手未必是末路
You said that losing my hands didn't have to be the end,
也可以是開端
that it could be a beginning.
對
Yeah.
因為還有其他方式可以拯救生命
Because there are other ways to save lives.
更艱難的方式
A harder way.
更怪異的方式
A weirder way.
帕爾默醫生  請前往急診室
Dr. Palmer, to the ER, please. Dr. Palmer, to the ER.
我不希望你走
I don't want you to go.
停下
Stop.
香港
好好選擇武器
Choose your weapon wisely.
誰都別想闖進圣殿
No one steps foot in this Sanctum.
誰都別想
No one.
卡西利亞斯
Kaecilius.
你站錯了隊  王
You're on the wrong side of history, Wong.
-她死了  -你是對的
- She's dead. - You were right.
她并不是我以為的那樣
She wasn't who I thought she was.
她很復雜
She was complicated.
復雜
Complicated?
黑暗次元不穩定
The Dark Dimension is volatile.
危險
Dangerous.
如果她被控制了呢
What if it overtook her?
她教導我們那是禁忌
She taught us it was forbidden,
她自己卻汲取其能量  來盜取數世紀的壽命
while she drew on its power to steal centuries of life.
她做了她以為正確的事
She did what she thought was right.
代價終究會來
The bill comes due.
你還不明白嗎
Don't you see?
她的犯忌導致狂熱信徒投向多瑪姆
Her transgressions led the zealots to Dormammu.
卡西利亞斯
Kaecilius
是她的錯
was her fault.
而我們現在  就在面對她欺瞞的后果
And here we are, in the consequence of her deception.
浴火的世界
A world on fire.
莫多  倫敦圣殿已經淪陷
Mordo,London Sanctum has fallen.
紐約圣殿也兩次遭到襲擊
The New York one has been attacked. Twice.
你清楚他們接下來要去哪
You know where they're going next.
香港
Hong Kong.
你曾叫我戰斗  就好像我命系于此
You told me once to fight like my life depended on it,
因為有一天  或許真會如此
because one day, it might.
那一天已經到來
Well, today is that day.
我不能一個人打敗他們
I cannot defeat them alone.
圣殿已經淪陷
The Sanctum's already fallen.
黑暗次元
The Dark Dimension.
多瑪姆來了
Dormammu is coming.
太遲了
It's too late.
沒有什么能阻止他了
Nothing can stop him.
未必
Not necessarily.
不
No.
咒語起效了
The spell's working.
我們有第二次機會
We've got a second chance.
不
No!
王
Wong!
打破自然法則  我知道
Breaking the laws of nature, I know.
別現在停下
Well, don't stop now.
等圣殿復原
When the Sanctum is restored,
他們會再次發起攻擊  我們得守住
they'll attack it again. We've gotta defend it.
走吧
Come on!
起來  斯特蘭奇  起來戰斗
Get up, Strange. Get up and fight!
我們可以做個了結
We can finish this.
你無法抵抗不可避免之事
You can't fight the inevitable.
多美啊
Isn't it beautiful?
超越時間的世界
A world beyond time.
超越死亡
Beyond death.
超越時間
Beyond time...
斯特蘭奇
Strange!
他走了
He's gone.
就連斯特蘭奇也拋下你們  屈服于他的力量
Even Strange has left you and surrendered to his power.
多瑪姆  我來談條件
Dormammu! I've come to bargain.
你是來受死的
You've come to die.
你的世界現在是我的了
Your world is now my world,
就像所有世界一樣
like all worlds.
多瑪姆  我來談條件
Dormammu! I've come to bargain.
你是來受死的
You've come to die.
你的世界現在是我的了...
Your world is now my...
這怎么回事
What is this?
幻覺嗎
Illusion?
-不  是真的  -那就好
- No, this is real. - Good.
多瑪姆  我來談條件
Dormammu! I've come to bargain.
你...怎么回事
You've... what is happening?
就像你給卡西利亞斯你的次元的力量
Just as you gave Kaecilius powers from your dimension,
我也從我的世界帶來了一份力量
I brought a little power from mine.
這是時間
This is time.
無盡循環的時間
Endless looped time.
你好大膽
You dare!
該死...
Oh, fu...
多瑪姆  我來談條件
Dormammu! I've come to bargain.
你不能永遠這么做
You cannot do this forever.
其實  我能
Actually, I can.
現在就這樣了
This is how things are now.
你和我  困在這一刻里  無窮無盡
You and me, trapped in this moment, endlessly.
那你就永生永世地死吧
Then you will spend eternity dying.
是啊  但地球上的人都能得以存活
Yes. But everyone on Earth will live.
但你會受盡折磨
But you will suffer.
痛苦跟我很熟了
Pain's an old friend.
多瑪姆
Dormammu!
-我來談條件  -停下
- I've come to bargain. - End this!
多瑪姆
Dormammu!
你永遠不會贏的
You will never win.
是啊
No...
但我可以輸
But I can lose.
一遍
Again,
又一遍
and again,
無窮
無盡  直到永遠
and again, forever.
-那樣你就是我的囚徒  -不
- And that makes you my prisoner. - No.
停下
Stop!
停下來
Make this stop!!!
放了我
Set me free!
不
No.
我來談條件
I've come to bargain.
你想要什么
What do you want?
把你的狂熱信徒從地球上帶走
Take your zealots from the Earth.
結束你對我的世界的襲擊
End your assault on my world.
永遠別回來
Never come back.
照做  我就結束循環
Do it, and I'll break the loop.
起來  斯特蘭奇
Get up, Strange.
起來戰斗
Get up and fight!
我們可以做個了結
We can finish this.
多美啊
Isn't it beautiful?
超越時間的世界
A world beyond time.
超越死亡
Beyond death.
-你做了什么  -我談妥了條件
- What have you done? - I made a bargain.
這是怎么回事
What is this?
這是
Well, it's,
你想要的一切
it's everything you've ever wanted.
永生  成為唯一的一部分
Eternal life as part of the One.
你不會喜歡的
You're not gonna like it.
你真該把整本書偷走的
You know, you really should have stolen the whole book,
因為警告
because the warnings...
警告是寫在咒語后面的
the warnings come after the spells.
真好笑
That's funny.
我們成功了
We did it.
是啊
Yes.
我們成功了
Yes, we did it.
也是靠違反自然法則
By also violating the natural laws.
看看你周圍  都結束了
Look around you. It's over.
你還是覺得不會產生后果嗎  斯特蘭奇
You still think there will be no consequences, Strange?
不會有代價
No price to pay?
我們跟她一樣  打破了法則
We broke our rules, just like her.
代價終究會來
The bill comes due.
總會來的
Always.
總有清算的一天
A reckoning.
我不會再走這條路了
I will follow this path no longer.
好吧
Yeah, okay.
明智之舉
Wise choice.
你今后還會有機會戴阿戈摩托之眼
You'll wear the eye of Agamotto
等你掌握其法力之后
once you've mastered its powers.
在那之前
Until then,
最好別戴著無限寶石滿街亂跑
best not to walk the streets wearing an infinity stone.
什么
A what?
你或許有魔法天賦
You might have a gift for the mystic arts,
但你還有很多要學
but you still have much to learn.
古一法師的死
Word of the Ancient One's death
很快將在多元宇宙里傳開
will spread through the multiverse.
地球沒有至尊法師維護了
Earth has no Sorcerer Supreme to defend it.
-我們必須做好準備  -我們會的
- We must be ready. - We'll be ready.
奇異博士
地球上現在還有魔法師了
So, Earth has wizards now, huh?
喝茶嗎
Tea?
我不喝茶
I don't drink tea.
你喝什么
What do you drink?
不喝茶
Not tea.
我有一份關注名單  都是來自
So, I keep a watchlist of individuals and beings
其他世界  可能對這個世界構成威脅的人
from other realms that may be a threat to this world.
你的領養弟弟  洛基  就是其中之一
Your adopted brother, Loki, is one of those beings.
-的確該加上他  -嗯
- Worthy inclusion. - Yeah.
為什么帶他來紐約
So, why bring him here to New York?
這說來話長
It's a bit of a long story.
家庭鬧劇  之類的
Family drama, that kind of thing, but...
我們在找我父親
we're looking for my father.
好吧  如果你們找到了奧丁
Oh, okay. So, if you found Odin,
你們都會馬上回阿斯加德嗎
you'd all return to Asgard, promptly?
是的  馬上
Oh, yes. Promptly.
太好了
Great.
我來幫你吧
Allow me to help you.
有事嗎
Can I help you?
他們拿擔架把你抬去了卡馬塔奇
They carried you into Kamar-Taj on a strecher.
瞧瞧你現在的樣子  潘伯恩
Look at you now. Pangborn.
莫多
Mordo.
我能為你做什么  哥們
So, what can I do for you, Man?
我離開了數月  想通了一件事
I've been away for many months now and I've had a revelation.
魔法師的真正意圖
The true purpose of a sorcerer
就是扭曲事物應有的形態
is to twist things out of there proper shape.
盜取能量
Stealing power,
敗壞自然
perverting nature...
就像你
like you.
我沒偷什么  這是我的力量
I've stolen nothing. This is my power.
我的
Mine.
力量
Power...
是有目的的
has a purpose.
你為什么這么做
Why are you doing this?
因為我終于明白這世界的問題出在哪了
Because I see at long last what's wrong with the world.
有太多魔法師
Too many sorcerers.
奇異博士還將回歸